Guide to the League for Industrial Democracy Records TAM.049
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Addendum, 1947-1996
  - Box 46, 1964-1972
    This box contains materials generated by LID, it includes materials on the conference on the Campus Crisis, including proposals, the continuation committee and steering committee materials; 1969, 1972 annual conference; LID's publication committee; Academic Committee of Correspondence; Lane Kirkland pamphlet and speech; discount book service; Student-Labor Institute Fund Appeal materials; University of Virginia Institute on Labor publicity, lectures, and press releases; publications committee materials; Ben Seligman and Aaron Levenstein materials on automation; and Steve Max reports; the Lenaghan report on on the Inter-American Organizing Conference; Dissent Conference; Brotherhood-In-Action conference; League of Industrial Democracy Manifesto; Congress of Racial Equality materials; Johnson-Humphrey-Kennedy Campaign Committee materials; Christman Youth Conference, "Issues for the Seventies: A Conference for Democratic Youth" materials; board meeting documentation; and membership drive materials.
  - Box 47, 1962-1969
    This box contains materials generated by the LID, including a new Left bibliography; LID work with United Federation of Teachers, including materials on the 1968 teachers strike; Labor Journalism Intern Project; Southern Student Organizing Committee; Upton Sinclair fundraising efforts; Institute on the Democratic Left materials; Urban Training Center with the Harlem Neighborhood Association; New Politics accusation of LID of receiving funds from the CIA; Youth Committee Against Poverty materials;; University of Virginia Institute on Labor fundraising, student applications; Housing for the Poor project; "Teacher Power" pamphlet; publications committee correspondence; "Urban School Crisis" pamphlet publication materials; 1966 annual conference; finance committee fundraising activities; board and executive committee notes and minutes; LID's Leadership Training Institute planning and publicity materials; Civil Rights Institute publicity and report; and an Arthur McDowell memo accusing the LID to providing cover to a Communist front group (Students for a Democratic Society) and ensuing controversy.
  - Box 48, 1947-1974
    This box contains material generated by LID, including correspondence to gain support to right a protest letter against Staughton Lynd; post office permits; material on Irving Howe's paper, "On the Nature of Communism and Relations with Communists" from the Looking Forward series; 1967 annual conference; Attitudes Toward Communism, Anti-Communism, Anti-anti-Communism Forum; Civil Rights Training Institute faculty correspondence, curriculum; "Automation and the Future Society" by Ben Seligman drafts; Table of Contents for Poverty and Human Resources Abstracts by Joyce Kornbluh and Alan Haber; materials on potential merger of Dissent and LID; national high school debate on nuclear arms control; board of directors and executive committee notes and minutes; 1972-1974 annual conferences planning materials; March for a Million School Children; New Politics Conference; Student-Labor Institute program fundraising appeal; Recruitment and Training Program seminar series; Conference on Youth and Democratic Values; Congress of Racial Equality; International Affairs Conference packet; Tom Milstein generated materials; and their More Effective Schools campaign.
  - Box 49, 1970-1976
    This box contains 1972, 1974 annual conference planning materials; board of directors and executive committee notes and minutes; Farah Manufacturing Company Strike solidarity and boycott materials; Oneita Knitting Mills strike solidarity materials; "Black Builders" job program pamphlet; Meany award sponsors; Student Institute on the Trade Union (in West Virginia) movement planning materials; youth recruitment; CUNY for Hugh Carey campaign; Gary Student-Labor Institute planning materials; Topeka Student-Labor Institute planning materials; Boston Student-Labor Institute; South Carolina Student-Labor Institute; Youth Coalition; Osh-Kosh Student Labor Institute; Frontlash high school Voter Registration campaign planning materials; Youth Vote Project Art Poster Contest; and 1974 Frontlash conference.
  - Box 50, 1960s-1987
    Neighborhood Youth Corps. programs; Frontlash fundraising materials, Frontlash 1975 conference; Citizens Committee youth activities; Farah strike support; 1976 annual conference planning materials; Board of Directors and Executive committee minutes and other notes; League of Industrial Democracy History file; Clippings file on Black Unemployment; New Left articles; "Will Labor come in from the Cold War" article by David Woberg; Eastern European Democracy program; Ed Koch Meeting notes; Heritage Foundation correspondence; Social Democrats materials; Tamiment Library bulletins; Bayard Rustin birthday dinner; funder correspondence; and collective bargaining agreements.
  - Box 51, 1967-1992
    This box contains a proposal to the Lynde and Harry Bradley Foundation and Smith-Richardson on the study of communist systems; board and executive meeting minutes and notes; international affairs travel grants; bequests to the League of Industrial Democracy; lists; Ansonia Club materials; Theodore Roberts claim against LID; Looking Forward Issues 2, 4-11, 16-18; Correspondence files A-Z (missing L); campaign issues clippings; Henry M. Jackson presidential campaign materials and New York primary; Labor for Carey Committee materials; Washington DC forum series notices; opposition campaign clippings; Lincoln Square Community Council issues and action; support materials and fundraising for Bella Abzug, Samets cocktail party planning; correspondence with Institute for Democracy in Eastern Europe
  - Box 52, 1971-1992
    This box includes materials including "Study on the Relationship between Social Democratic Political Parties and ICFTU [International Confederation of Free Trade Unions]-Affiliated Trade Unions: The Impact on Policy" Middle East, Caribbean, Africa, Asia, South Pacific, and Europe reports; campaign publications and research papers; and LID member and contributor card files (organized alphabetically and by state).
  - Membership and Contributor Cards, 1949-1993 (Box 52, Box 53, Box 54)
  - Box 55, 1951-1997
    This box contains materials generated by the League for Industrial Democracy, including "Labor in the 90's" packet; International Labor Organization materials and correspondence; Malawi protest in response to the arrest of Frederick Chiluba; Coca Cola boycott; United Nations materials; German Marshall Fund correspondence; general correspondence files; Concerned Citizens of the Delaware Valley circular; Child Labor Coalition conference materials; "Women and Work" draft; Leadership Seminar correspondence; fundraising appeals and contributions; member lists; Jewish Labor Committee background materials, correspondence with the Attorney General's office; The Federationist subscriptions and other materials; LID Training Conference in May 1967 in New York City materials; "The Economics of Equality" preparation and promotional materials; 1962-1963 conference materials; poverty program; fundraising appeals, including a letter from Bayard Rustin; LID Institute for Civil Rights Activists; Northern Student Movement-Harlem Action Group Institute; South Jamaica Congress of Racial Equality Institute; League for Industrial Democracy-Workers Defense League Joint Finances; Bayard Rustin writings; Harrington Reception planning materials; and Harry W. Laidler 80th Birthday and 1964 conference materials.
  - Box 55, 1962-1976 (Box 56)
    This box contains materials generated by LID, including 1962, 1965 annual conference; Bayard Rustin meeting and speaking materials; LID National Program materials; "Racism in Southern Labor Relations" study and correspondence; Urban Democracy committee materials; check requisitions; Labor Summer Schools correspondence; Frontlash Training Institute participant profiles; proposals and brochures; Washington Student Labor Institute student applications; Goddard Labor Institute student applications and correspondence; youth groups fliers and other materials; sample letters; thank you letters; Student-Labor Institute Program; labor union fundraising; conference time schedules; conference costs and housing arrangements; Leadership Training Institute in Front Royale, Virginia; Kentucky Youth-Labor Institute; and San Francisco Youth-Labor Institute; Gary, Indiana Youth-Labor Institute; Philadelphia Youth-Labor Institute; Columbus, and Ohio Youth-Labor Institute.
  - Box 57, 1954-1976
    Little Rock Youth-Labor Institute; Florida Institute; West Virginia Training Institute; Los Angeles Youth-Labor Institute; Council of Jewish Federation and Welfare Funds correspondence; Student-Labor Institute evaluations; mailings to Institute participants; Student Labor Institute Committee reports; press releases; San Francisco Frontlash materials; fundraising letters and sources; press coverage; six folders of loose materials including meeting minutes, Student League for Industrial Democracy newsletters, circulars, news bulletins, and other materials; pamphlets; "Youth and Democratic Change in the Americas" pamphlet and drafts; Youth Project on Democratic Change materials, correspondence, AFL-CIO mailings, and California Office/David Jessup records.
  - Box 58, 1966-1975
    This box contains materials on the Youth Project on Democratic Change survey materials, mailings, New York and Vermont conference materials, and expenses; Academic Committee of Correspondence materials; United Federation of Teachers 1968 strike literature, statement, and correspondence; Task Force on School Decentralization materials; meeting minutes; fund appeals; New School lecture series promotional materials; Housing for the Poor conference and project; LID institute on "The Trade Union Movement and the New South" at the University of Virginia follow-up materials; Youth Committee/Citizens' Committee to Support the G.E. Workers publicity; Poor People's campaign; 1975 annual conference tickets, journal, housing, speeches; and LID Booklet on Soviet Dissident Writings planning materials.
  - Box 59, 1967-1975
    This box contains materials from the 1972, 1975 annual conference; board and executive committee meeting minutes; LID Booklet on Soviet Dissident Writings proposal; Academic Committee of Correspondence materials; WEVD program "Can Anyone Run a City?" planning materials; Farah Workers contact list and correspondence; Student Campaign in Support of Open Enrollment with Maintenance of Standards at the City University proposal and other materials; Labor-Social issues Luncheon planning materials; Leon Keyserling speech; Christmas Youth Conference; Educational Seminars for Prospective Local School Board Candidates; AFL-CIO Intern program; New Jersey Student Labor Committee evaluations and other materials; Youth Vote Project; luncheons for the South Vietnamese, New School for trade unionists, labor relations, group legal services; Black Builders program; Board of Education hearings; publications committee; and the Herbert Hill and Donald Slaiman debate.
  - Box 60, 1961-1971
    This box contains board of directors and executive committee meeting minutes; Herbert Hill New School speech; "Labor Breakthrough in the Southern Classroom: University of Virginia" pamphlet; Working for Democratic Change in the Americas program; 1968-1969 annual conference materials; Washington DC chapter correspondence; Inter-American Youth Conference publications; Young People's Socialist League materials; Youth Project on Democratic Change materials; LID's 1963 national program; university workshops; "The State of the Student Movement-1970" report; Youth Committee/Citizens' Committee to Support the G.E. Workers correspondence; "Democratic Change" newsletters; report on the "Consultation on Youth and Democratic Change;" and the "Youth and the New York State Elections" project.
  - Box 61, 1968-1976
    This box contains materials from New Jersey, Tennessee Democratic Change conferences; Youth Committee/Citizens' Committee to Support the G.E. Workers clippings; Latin America file; Working for Democratic Change in the Americas Conference planning materials; Latin America pamphlet draft materials; Board and Executive Committee meeting minutes; 1970-1971 annual conference materials; Apprenticeship program and course materials; Workmen's Circle and Circle Lodge lecture series; "A Study Program for the Elderly and Friends of the Elderly: An Interdisciplinary Approach to Help Make Democracy Work for Old People" packet by Hope Sabin Bagger; Voter registration project from the 1976 election; and the Europe-America Conference materials.
  - Box 62, 1963-1984
    This box contains three reports, "Humanizing the Research Interview: A Posthumous Analysis of LeRoy Bowman's Approach to the Interview Process" by Barbara Bowman, Garda Bowman, and Ruth Resch, "Conference on the Campus Crisis," and "Consultation on Youth and Democratic Change;" Norman Thomas by Robert J. Alexander manuscript; "Harry W. Laidler and the Intercollegiate Socialist Society" by Carmela Ascolese Karnoutsos dissertation; California, West Virginia, North Carolina, and Amherst Student Labor Institutes; Democratic Change newsletters from 1970-1975; Norman Thomas 80th Birthday Committee; 1966 annual conference materials; discussion and debate in regards to the Thomas Brooks pamphlet, "To Build a New World;" Organizing the Poor: The Alinsky model vs. the New Careers model debate between Jay Schulman and Frank Reissman; Dissent discussion group materials; Shanker Forum; "The Problem of the New Left" by Tom Kahn from the Looking Forward series; Conference on Economic planning; board of directors and executive committee meeting minutes; Student Labor conference; "The Second Southern Revolution" by Vera Rony; Pat Sexton pamphlet on schools; Ad-Hoc Committee to Defend the Right to Teach; and G.E. Strikers literature.
  - Box 63, 1967-1996
    This box contains correspondence on the United Federation of Teachers 1968 strike and Freedom to Teach Act; board of directors and executive committee meeting minutes; "Automation and Future Society" pamphlet by Seligman; Trade Unionists Luncheons; photographs; expenses from Student Labor Institutes; materials from the Eastern European Youth Exchange Study tour; European Union Youth Exchange Phase II, German Marshall Fund expenses; materials on Romania and the Student League from the Politechnical Institute of Bucharest and Affiliates; American Federation of Teachers promotional materials; "Romanian Campaign and Election Monitoring Training and Pre-Election Assessment Delegation" report; board and executive committee minutes; Youth Democracy Conference; and administrative, financial and membership files from the late 1980s and early 1990s.
  - Box 64, 1989-1992
    This box contains materials on the Eastern European Youth Exchange program proposals, agendas, finances; Student League of Romania trainings and team files; Education for Democracy project of the american Federation of Teachers, Educational Excellence Network, and Freedom House; photographs; Romania campaign; German Marshall Fund grant to the League for Industrial Democracy for Romania; Lane Kirkland trip to Poland; LID Young Socialist Democrats conferences, contributors; Eastern Europe Trip report and related files, photos, speakers, and conferences; and Romanian Election Monitoring.
  - Box 65, undated
    Oversize clippings and cuttings on unemployment.
- Series III: Photographs, 1950s-1960s
  This series contains mostly black-and-white photographs of individuals and events, from the 1950s-1970s. This series also contains photographs from a disassembled scrapbook and negatives. There are also autographed photographs and graphic portraits which appear to be collected by Louise Adams Grant Floyd. These photographs depict Harriet Stanton Blatch, George W. Coleman, Alexander Devine, J.T. "Red" Doran, Jim Lrkin, James Johnson, S.K. Ratcliffe, Albert Rhys Williams, H.G. Wells, Jesse Lynch Williams, Art Young, and Charles Zueblin.
  Arranged alphabetically, then by type of material.
  - Abrams, Charles, undated (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Aronson, Arnold, undated (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Attlee, [Clement], undated (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Bardacke, Judy, undated (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Bernstein, Jules, undated (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Bloomstein, Charles, undated (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Bookbinder, Hyman, undated (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Bowles, Chester, undated (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Brooks, Thomas R., undated (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Coldwell, M.J., undated (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Cole, M.I. [Mr. and Mrs.?], undated (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Counts, George, undated (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Davies, undated (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - Debs, [Eugene], undated (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Dewey, John (90th Birthday party and one small portrait from earlier), undated (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - DiLorenzo, Jeanette, undated (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - Douglas, Senator Paul H., undated (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - Douglas, Thomas C., undated (Box 66, Folder 18)
  - Dubinsky, David, undated (Box 66, Folder 19)
  - Duffey, Joseph, undated (Box 66, Folder 20)
  - Fainberg, Victor, undated (Box 66, Folder 21)
  - Farmer, James, undated (Box 66, Folder 22)
  - Fischer, Louis, undated (Box 66, Folder 23)
  - Gaitskell, [Hugh], undated (Box 66, Folder 24)
  - Gans, Herb, undated (Box 66, Folder 25)
  - Gilmore, Robert W., undated (Box 66, Folder 26)
  - Goldberg, Arthur, undated (Box 66, Folder 27)
  - Goldfinger, Nathaniel, undated (Box 66, Folder 28)
  - Gotbaum, Victor, undated (Box 66, Folder 29)
  - Gray, Ed, undated (Box 66, Folder 30)
  - Green, Ernest, undated (Box 66, Folder 31)
  - Harrington, Donald, undated (Box 66, Folder 32)
  - Hayes, AJ, undated (Box 66, Folder 33)
  - Henderson, Vivian, undated (Box 66, Folder 34)
  - Hill, Norman, undated (Box 66, Folder 35)
  - Hillquit, Morris, undated (Box 66, Folder 36)
  - Ivanov, Valentin, undated (Box 66, Folder 37)
  - Jennings, Paul, undated (Box 66, Folder 38)
  - Keenleyside, undated (Box 66, Folder 39)
  - Keyserling, Leon, undated (Box 66, Folder 40)
  - Kheel, Ted, undated (Box 66, Folder 41)
  - Kirkland, Lane, undated (Box 66, Folder 42)
  - Kugler, Israel, undated (Box 66, Folder 43)
  - Lipset, S[eymour] M., undated (Box 66, Folder 44)
  - Lipsig, James, undated (Box 66, Folder 45)
  - Lopatin, Harry, undated (Box 66, Folder 46)
  - Lynd, Staughton, undated (Box 66, Folder 47)
  - Manson, Julius, undated (Box 66, Folder 48)
  - Matos, Huber, undated (Box 66, Folder 49)
  - Mazey, Emil, undated (Box 66, Folder 50)
  - McNamara, James, undated (Box 66, Folder 51)
  - Mihajlov, Mihajlo, undated (Box 66, Folder 52)
  - Minkoff, [Isaiah], undated (Box 66, Folder 53)
  - Naumoff, undated (Box 66, Folder 54)
  - Neier, Aryeh, undated (Box 66, Folder 55)
  - O'Neal, Frederick, undated (Box 66, Folder 56)
  - Podhoretz, Norman, undated (Box 66, Folder 57)
  - Randolph, A. Philip, undated (Box 66, Folder 58)
  - Roosevelt, Mrs. Eleanor, undated (Box 66, Folder 59)
  - Rustin, Bayard, undated (Box 66, Folder 60)
  - Samuel, Howard D., undated (Box 66, Folder 61)
  - Seidman, Burt, undated (Box 66, Folder 62)
  - Shachtman, Max, undated (Box 66, Folder 63)
  - Shanker, Al, undated (Box 66, Folder 64)
  - Shaw, [George Bernard], undated (Box 66, Folder 65)
  - Sinclair, Upton, undated (Box 66, Folder 66)
  - Slaiman, Don, undated (Box 66, Folder 67)
  - Starr, Mark, undated (Box 66, Folder 68)
  - Stern, William, undated (Box 66, Folder 69)
  - Suall, Irwin, undated (Box 66, Folder 70)
  - Sviridoff, Mitchell, undated (Box 66, Folder 71)
  - Thomas, Norman, undated (Box 66, Folder 72)
  - Tyler, Gus, undated (Box 66, Folder 73)
  - Von Arsdale, Harry, undated (Box 66, Folder 75)
  - Waksman, Selman, undated (Box 66, Folder 75)
  - Weisenberg, Mina, undated (Box 66, Folder 76)
  - Wilkinson, Ellen, undated (Box 66, Folder 77)
  - Waskow, Arthur, undated (Box 66, Folder 78)
  - Zack, Al, undated (Box 66, Folder 79)
  - Djilas Meeting, undated (Box 67, Folder 80)
  - Feldman-Gershman Campaign – Citizens Committee, undated (Box 67, Folder 81)
  - G.E. Strike, undated (Box 67, Folder 82)
  - Goddard College Institute, undated (Box 67, Folder 83)
  - Harrington Installation 1964 (Box 67, Folder 84)
  - Intercollegiate Socialist Society, undated (Box 67, Folder 85)
  - Labor Forums, undated (Box 67, Folder 86)
  - N.Y. Chapter Meetings, undated (Box 67, Folder 87)
  - Oneita Strike Picketing, 1973 (Box 67, Folder 88)
  - R-T-P Series, 1974 (Box 67, Folder 89)
  - SLI Washington, D.C., 1971 (Box 67, Folder 90)
  - Student Labor Institute, undated (Box 67, Folder 91)
  - Student Labor Institute Ridgewood, N.Y., 1973 (Box 67, Folder 92)
  - Student Labor Institute West Virginia 1970 (Box 67, Folder 93)
  - Louise Adams Grant Floyd's autographed photographs and graphic portraits, undated (Box 67, Folder 94)
  - Photos from Disassembled Scrapbook [1 of 2], undated (Box 67, Folder 95)
  - Photos from Disassembled Scrapbook [2 of 2], undated (Box 67, Folder 96)
  - Photocopies of Original Photo Scrapbook Pages, undated (Box 67, Folder 97)
  - Fortieth Anniversary Dinner, 1945 February 3; 1 folder (Box Tamiment Shared XOS001)
  - Negatives, undated (Box 67, Folder 98)